var astronomydata = {
  "total_size": 4,
  "questions": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "The planet nearest to the Earth is?",
      "option1": "Mars",
      "option2": "Jupiter",
      "option3": "Mercury",
      "option4": "Venus",
      "ans": "d",
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Which of the following does not belong to solar system?",
      "option1": "Planets",
      "option2": "Nebulae",
      "option3": "Comets",
      "option4": "Asteroids",
      "ans": "b",
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "Which of the following planets is called “Blue planet”?",
      "option1": "Uranus",
      "option2": "Mercury",
      "option3": "Earth",
      "option4": "Venus",
      "ans": "c",
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question":
          "which one of the following planets takes the same number of days for rotation and revolution?",
      "option1": "Jupiter",
      "option2": "Mars",
      "option3": "Venus",
      "option4": "Mercury",
      "ans": "d",
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question":
          "The unit of measuring distances between the stars is known as?",
      "option1": "Light unit",
      "option2": "Stellar unit",
      "option3": "Cosmic unit",
      "option4": "Galactic unit",
      "ans": "a",
    },
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question":
          "The position of a planet when it is nearest to the Sun is called",
      "option1": "Apogee",
      "option2": "Aphelion",
      "option3": "Perigee",
      "option4": "Perihelion",
      "ans": "d",
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "What is the mass of the Sun?",
      "option1": "1.5×10 Power 30 Kg",
      "option2": "1.98×10 Power 30 Kg",
      "option3": "4.8×10 Power 30 Kg",
      "option4": "8×10 Power 30 Kg",
      "ans": "b",
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "Which is the nearest star to our sun?",
      "option1": "Proxima Centurai",
      "option2": "Alpha Scorpii",
      "option3": "Beta Orionis",
      "option4": "Vega",
      "ans": "a",
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "Which planet has the smallest diameter?",
      "option1": "Mercury",
      "option2": "Mars",
      "option3": "Pluto",
      "option4": "Venus",
      "ans": "d",
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question":
          "On which of the following planets of the solar system does the sun rise in the west and set in the east?",
      "option1": "Saturn",
      "option2": "Mars",
      "option3": "Jupiter",
      "option4": "Venus",
      "ans": "d",
    },
  ]
};
